Council of Connecticut Academic Library Directors Records
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Council of Connecticut Academic Library Directors Records.
1993-1998.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Council of Connecticut Academic Library Directors.
.75 linear feet.
MSS19980355
In June 1993, Dorothy Kijanka, Director of the Ryan Matura Library at Sacred Heart University, convened a group of library directors with the hope of forming a consortium, loosely modeled on WALDO, the Westchester Academic Library Directors Organization. Like the Westchester group, the envisioned Connecticut consortium would explore avenues of interlibrary cooperation, jointly seek grant funding, and serve as a forum for the discussion of mutual concerns.
History
In June 1993, Dorothy Kijanka, Director of the Ryan Matura Library at Sacred Heart University, convened a group of library directors with the hope of forming a consortium, loosely modeled on WALDO, the Westchester Academic Library Directors Organization. Like the Westchester group, the envisioned Connecticut consortium would explore avenues of interlibrary cooperation, jointly seek grant funding, and serve as a forum for the discussion of mutual concerns.
The purpose of the Council, as stated in the by-laws, are
• to improve services and access to resources through cooperation
• to benefit economically by bargaining/purchasing/applying for grants collectively
• to serve as a means of communication among Connecticut academic library directors to make recommendations and represent the point of view of Connecticut academic library directors to any agency affecting their library service.
Membership in the group is open to the directors of all Connecticut academic libraries, regardless of the institution's governance, source of funding, or constituency.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of correspondence, announcements, agendas and minutes of meetings. Annual reports of the Council's activities began in 1994 and continue through 1998. The organization is still in existence and periodic transfers of similar materials are expected.
Arrangement
Series I: Annual Reports ( 1994-1998 )
Series II: Minutes ( 1993-1998 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a collection of materials pertaining to professional organizations, with a connection to the University, based in Connecticut. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Orgnizations:
Council of Connecticut Academic Library Directors.
Subjects:
Librarians--Connecticut--Societies, etc.; Library directors--Connecticut--Societies, etc.; Library cooperation--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Minutes.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Reports.
Occupations:
Professional organization.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated to Archives & Special Collections by the Council in November 1998.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Annual Reports, 1994-1998
  - Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
- Series II: Minutes, 1993-1998
  - 1993 June (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1993 October (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1993 November (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1993 December (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1994 March (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1994 April (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1994 May (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1994 July (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1994 September (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 1994 October (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - 1994 November (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - 1994 December (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - 1995 February (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - 1995 March (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - 1995 April (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - 1995 May (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - 1995 June (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - 1995 September (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - 1995 October (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - 1995 November (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - 1995 December (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - 1996 February (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - 1996 March (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - 1996 April (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - 1996 May (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - 1996 June (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - 1996 September (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - 1996 October (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - 1996 November (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - 1996 December (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - 1997 February (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - 1997 March (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - 1997 April (Box 2:, Folder 37)
  - 1997 May (Box 2:, Folder 38)
  - 1997 June (Box 2:, Folder 39)
  - 1997 September (Box 2:, Folder 40)
  - 1997 October (Box 2:, Folder 41)
  - 1997 November (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - 1997 December (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - 1998 February (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - 1998 March (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - 1998 April (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - 1998 May (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - 1998 June (Box 2:, Folder 48)